Tampere, Finland +358504805190 junsheng.fu@tut.fi

# Junsheng Fu

GitHub LinkedIn Patents

I am an experienced researcher, a quick learner and a problem solver, passionate about autonomous driving, with 8 patents applications and 4 papers. I like to think "what if" and "how to", and enjoy applying Computer Vision and Deep Learning techniques to solve the challenges in autonomous driving.

#### **Technical skills**

Languages: Python, C/C++, Matlab

Frameworks: TensorFlow, Keras, CUDA, Numpy, Scikit-learn, OpenCV

Others: Camera calibration, Structure-from-motion, SLAM, Tracking, Machine Learning, Git, Linux

## **Projects**

Vehicle detection and tracking

Code, Video

4.2017

- Created vehicle detection and tracking pipeline with two approaches, deep neural networks (YOLO+TensorFlow) and support vector machines (HOG+OpenCV).
- Optimized and evaluated the model on video data from both highway and city driving.

Extended kalman filter-based tracking Code, Video

4.2017

- Designed and implemented an Extended Kalman Filter for object tracking with C++.
- Utilized fused sensor data from both LIDAR and RADAR sensors.

Lane departure warning

Code, Video

3.2017

- · Designed and implemented a lane-finding algorithm and a lane-departure-warning system.
- · Identified lane curvature and overcame environmental challenges, e.g. shadows, pavement changes.

Driving behavioral cloning

Code, Video

2.2017

- Built and trained a CNN to autonomously steer a car in a game simulator, using TensorFlow and Keras.
- Used optimization techniques such as regularization and dropout to generalize the network for driving on unseen tracks.

### **Experience**

Tampere University of Technology

**Doctoral Student** 

Finland | 1.2014-12.2017

- Implemented 6 autonomous driving demos with OpenCV and TensorFlow (videos).
- Working on camera pose estimation with LIDAR and street-view images.
- Served as teaching Assistant for "SGN-13006 Introduction to Pattern Recognition and Machine Learning", and got the best course reviews award from students in 2016 Fall Semester.

Nokia Research Center (Nokia Tech) Computer Vision Researcher

Finland | 3.2012-12.2015

- Designed and implemented a 3D Map Augmented Photo gallery application with HERE Map (video).
- Developed an Interactive Video Playback System with HERE Map (video).
- · Implemented 3D reconstruction and visualization systems for indoor 3D smart sensing.

Tampere University of Technology

**Research Assistant** 

Finland | 9.2010-12.2011

- Designed and implemented a real-time video denoising filter with C.
- Embedded a denoising filter into H.264/AVC codecs.

Demola

**Software Engineer** 

Finland | 3.2010-8.2010

· Implemented a face tracking application in Nokia N900 mobile phone with OpenCV and QT.

## **Education**

Tampere University of Technology, Finland - Computer Vision, Ph.D.	GPA: 4.83 / 5	2017
Tampere University of Technology, Finland - Signal Processing, M.Sc.	GPA: 4.45 / 5	2012
Hangzhou Dianzi University, China - Telecommunication, B.Eng.	GPA: 85 / 100	2009
Udacity - Self-Driving-Car Engineer Nanodegree		2017